"The Dollars?"
ダラーズ？
I don't really know much about them, either.
オレも詳しいことは分かんねぇんだけどよ
Anyway, there are a lot of them,
and I hear all of them have short tempers.
とにかく 人数が多くて線が一本ぶち切れたチームらしい
Being absent on your first day of school...
初日から欠席なんて…
I said I don't know!
知らないったら！
Anyway, don't go near Heiwajima Shizuo.
とにかく平和島静雄ってヤツには近づくなよ
Orihara Izaya?
おりはらいざや？
He's really dangerous, so definitely don't get involved with him.
こいつはやばいから絶対にかかわるなよ
Yeah, that's Simon.
ああ～ サイモンってさ
He works to pull customers into that Russian sushi bar.
そこのロシア人がやってる寿司屋の客引きやってんだ
Khorosho, khorosho!
ハラショー ハラショー！
It's Russian sushi.
ロシアズシよ
It's good.
ウマイよ ヤスイよ～！
It's cheap!
Hey, mister, don't run away.
おにいサン 逃げないネ！
Russian sushi!
ロシアズシよ～！
Excuse me.
Excuse me
Do you speak Russian?
Yes, I do.
Thank God.
How do I get to this place?
Ah, just go straight down this street.
Are you tourists?
Yes.
This is an enchanting city.
I'm sure you'll have a great time here.
Thank you very much.
If you have time, be sure to visit this restaurant.
Ikebukuro: a lively borough that spans both east and west.
To the north, there's a large-scale entertainment district.
北には大規模な歓楽街があり
They say that in one day over one million people visit this massive area.
１日に１００万人の人が集まるといわれている巨大な街 池袋
Ikeburuko...
This town is full of criminals.
この街は異邦人であふれている
Like him...
彼も そして彼女も
And her.
They come to this town looking for something,
seeking something, wanting to change something.
何かを探し 何かを求め この街にやってくる
何かを変えようと この街に…
The class representatives have yet to be determined, so would anyone like to run?
クラス委員がまだ決まってないが
誰か立候補する者はいないか？
A new town:
新しい街…
One where no one knows your past.
誰もかつての自分を知る者はいない
It's a chance for you to recreate yourself.
新しい自分になれるチャンス だが…
However...
Sonohara...Sonohara Anri, is it?
園原… 園原杏里か
Anyone else?
ほかはいないか？
Then the girls' representative is decided.
じゃあ 女子は決定
I'll leave the rest to you, Sonohara.
園原 あとは頼むな
Uh...umm...
あ… あの…
Are there any boys who want to be class representative?
それでは 男子でクラス委員をやりたい人 いませんか？
I want to do it, but it might also be a pain...
やってみたいような… でも めんどくさいような…
Yet I'd feel bad if someone else did it...
でも ほかの人にやられるのもなんだかしゃくなような…
You do it!
お前やれよ
You serious?!
えっ？ マジで オレ？
But I'd have to deal with her!
でもめんどくさくねぇ？
あいつの相手するんだぜ
Yes.
はい
Uh...umm...
I'm Ryugamine...Mikado.
竜ヶ峰… 帝人です
Sonohara!
園原さん
Um, about the meeting we have with the other classes, I've never done this sort of thing before, so...
あ… あの… 明日のほかのクラスとの連絡会だけど
僕 こういうのあんまりやったことなくて…
Excuse me! I've some business to attend to!
すみません！用があるので これで
I underestimated you.
お前も隅に置けないなぁ
I can't believe you'd proactively pursue a lovey-dovey rendezvous and try to hunt a girl down when,
小学校のときは幼なじみと噂を立てられただけで泣いてたお前が
in elementary school, you burst into tears when people
spread rumors about you and your childhood friend.
自分から積極的に
ラブラブ ランデブーでハンターチャンスとは
Yeah, yeah...
はいはい
But you're still naïve.
だが 最後のひと押しが甘い
Just because you came to Tokyo doesn't mean
your life will turn into a feel-good romantic comedy.
そんなこっちゃ せっかく東京出てきたって
ウハウハの学園ラブコメ生活は送れないね… っと
I-It's not like I...
別にそんなんじゃ…
On that note...let's go pick up some girls!
というわけで ナンパに行こう？
I'm in the now,
今こそ オレ？
I'm the future,
今から オレ？
And my time for popularity has come!
今 オレ モテ期到来みたいな～？
They'd never go for a high schooler.
そりゃ 高校生に誘われたってね…
People come to this town in search of change.
変化を求め この街にやってくる者たち
But change never comes easily.
だが そう簡単に変化など起こりはしない
Even if you try to change locations, you're still the old you.
場所が変わろうとも そこにいるのは確実に
昔のままの自分だ
What? No way.
ええ～ 嫌だ
I have a boyfriend anyway.
私 彼氏いるから
That doesn't matter! Just having some tea with a guy doesn't count as cheating.
関係ない！
ナンパされてお茶したって それは浮気のうちに入らないから～
Oh, hey, did you hear?
ねえねえ 知ってる？ ユミの新しい彼氏 ダラーズなんだって
Yumi's new boyfriend is in The Dollars.
What?! Really?!
ええ～ マジで～!?
I wonder if she's scared at all.
怖くないのかな？
How interesting! Let's talk about it over tea.
興味深いね～ お茶でも飲みながら ゆっくりと～
Aren't The Dollars like a biker gang or something?
ダラーズって 暴走族みたいなもん？
No, they don't ride bikes or anything.
There are some people in this town who perpetuate violence.
この街には徒党を組み
時に暴力的な行為を行う者がいる
They wear a specific color that signals what group they're in,
彼らはそれぞれの組織ごとに自分たちの象徴となる色を持っており
Otherwise known as "color gangs."
カラーギャングと呼ばれている
However, there's one gang that's been gaining prestige recently, yet has no identifying color.
しかし 昨今勢力を伸ばしている そのチームは
特定の色を持たない
But if you had to pick one, it'd be "clearly colorless."
強いていえば 無色透明
That's The Dollars' color.
それがダラーズのチームカラーだ
They communicate through their private website.
専用のウェブサイトを通じ 構成員を増やしていく
They say they're a special kind of group.
特殊なチームだといわれている
Oh yeah, there are rumors going around that
The Dollars are behind those recent slasher incidents, right?
あっ 最近起きてる切り裂き魔の事件もダラーズの仕業だって噂だよね
Oh, really?
えっ そうなの？
Like I said, we should talk about this more over some tea.
だから～ 詳しい話はお茶でもしながら～
I know a great place.
The Dollars?
ダラーズ？
Yes, I know that gang.
ええ 知ってますよ
What sort of people are in it?
The Dollars are amazing!
I heard they're getting involved with the Chinese mafia.
And the stabbing of that Yakuza guy was
also supposedly perpetrated by The Dollars.
Argh, this sucks.
まったく～ お前が暗い顔してるから
They all ran away because you were wearing that depressing expression.
逃げられちまったじゃないか
Kida!
紀田君～！
How goes it?
こんちは～っす
Um, you're the kid with the manga-style name...
ええっと～ 名前が漫画みたいな…
Mikado, right?
帝人君っすね！
Wanna go to Toranoana with us?
「とらのあな」一緒に行く？
Suji Yasuda's doing a signing there today!
今日は… スージー安田先生のサイン会っすよ～！
Don't yell stuff like that out loud.
そういう話を大声でするな
Huh? Why? What's wrong with talking about the artist Suji?
ええっ なんで？
スージー先生の話して…
The Dollars?
ダラーズ？
Yeah, I know the name...
はい 名前くらいなら…
I heard the rumor from my friend today...
Hmmm.
本当にあるチームでも あんまりそう言うのに
I've never seen them, so do they really exist?
Are you saying it's an Internet prank?
I don't know about that, but...
If they really do exist, I wouldn't want to get anywhere near them.
近付かない方がいいですよね
The Dollars?
ダラーズ？
They fight with the Flame Haze that's sealed in the basement of Sunshine 60, right?
サンシャイン６０の地下に
封印されたフレイムヘイズと日夜戦いを繰り広げているんっすよね!?
That's not it, Yuma-chi.
違うよ ゆまっち
They're angels that fly around going, "Pi, piru piru" and show their panties.
パンツを見せながら 空を飛ぶぴぴるぴるぴる天使だよ
Why're you asking about The Dollars?
どうしてダラーズのことなんか聞くんだ？
I can't really say...
どうしてって言われても…
You get scared after hearing those stories?
さっきの話 聞いててびびっちまったのか？
I've heard a lot of rumors, too.
オレもいろいろ噂は聞いている
They're a rather dangerous lot.
かなり危ないヤツらだってな
Is...that so?
そうなんですか？
You shouldn't approach them just out of curiosity.
興味本位で近づかない方がいい
Don't be overly inquisitive.
余計な詮索はよしておくことだな
You're so cool, Kadota!
門田さん 格好いい～！
You're totally like a mature main character who's just a bit cranky.
大人なムードの主人公の兄貴分キャラって感じ？
You'd be popular among girls who like middle-aged men.
おやじ好きな女子に人気なタイプ～？
No, no, no...
Shut up!
There are also areas in this town you shouldn't enter.
街には足を踏み入れてはいけない場所もある
You won't get sick!
オナカ 壊さないネ～！
Try it once!
一回試しに食べてみるヨ～
You won't die if you just try it once!
一回くらいナラ死なないヨ
Man, I'm hungry.
腹減ったなぁ
Yeah.
そうっすね
Let's get something to eat before we go to the next—
次の回収行く前に軽く…
It's the headless rider!
首なしライダー！
No way!
Huh?
うそ!?
I don't need any occult crap this early.
昼間っからオカルトかよ
She's working pretty hard.
頑張るなぁ
Some people get swallowed up by the city and disappear.
時に街に飲まれ姿を消す者もいる
And others search for them.
そんな誰かを必死に捜す者も…
I'll meet her. I'll definitely find her.
会える 必ず見つかる
My love will bring her to me.
オレの愛が彼女を呼び寄せてみせる
Is that Harima?
張間さん？
Harima!
張間さん！
I thought you were someone else! I'm sorry!
ひ… 人違いでした！ 失礼しました！
And this town is full of danger.
そして 街は危険であふれている
Hey.
ちょっと
Like here.
ここにも…
C'mon, let's get some tea.
ねえ とりあえずお茶しない？
And here.
そこにも…
He wanted to change.
変化を求めていたはずだった
You serious?!
マジかよ！
He felt like something would change in this new town, that something would happen.
新しい街で何かが変わるような
何かが起こるような気がしていた
But...
だが 自分を待っていたのは
The only thing waiting for him was a darkness hiding in the shadows of this bright city.
一見きらびやかな街の陰に潜む深い闇
He froze with fear.
足がすくむ
He feared he might not be able to live in this town.
本当に自分はこの街で生きていけるか…
おじけづく
I know how you feel!
お前の気持ちは分かる
Huh?
電車に乗れば 痴漢扱い
You're treated as a sexual pervert when you ride the train, people try to recruit you into cults wherever you go,
街を歩けば 怪しげな勧誘
you go home and get into trouble with your neighbors, and to top it off, there's The Dollars and the headless rider!
家に帰れば ご近所トラブル！
おまけにダラーズ 首なしライダー
That's the concrete jungle of Tokyo!
それが東京コンクリートジャングル！
But!
だが！ 乗り越えろ！
Overcome it!
You pledged to become a fine Ikebukuroer,
so show us all and overcome this tribulation!
立派な池袋人になると誓ったのなら
この試練を乗り越えてみせるのだ 帝人！
Mikado!
Ryugamine...Mikado!
竜ヶ峰… 帝人!!
Well, I'll be around, so there's no need to worry.
まっ オレがついてっから 心配すんなって
Kida...
紀田君…
And never forget to smile when you pick up girls. Smile.
それから ナンパのときは明るく笑顔 笑顔だ
But, I'm pretty sure it's impossible to pick up girls who're already part of the workforce.
でも 社会人をナンパするのはさすがに無理だと思うけど
What're you saying?
何言ってんの？
All we're trying to do is talk to them, so we're fine.
話しかけるの自体が目的だからいいんだよ
You're putting on airs even though Harima Mikawa's gone?
あんたさ
張間美香がいなくなったのに でかい顔してるみたいじゃない？
So you're a class representative?
クラス委員になったんだって？
She's getting bullied. And in a totally cliché way.
わっ いじめ！ しかも ものすごくベタな
My boyfriend's, like, here with me today.
With that much makeup on, they can't be too imposing.
ここまでコテコテだと さすがに怖くないかも
Kyoko's boyfriend's in The Dollars, you know.
陽子の彼氏 ダラーズなんだよ
Hiroshi!
ヒロシ！
Yo, yo! You talkin' to one ov da Dollahs here! Let's get it on! Yeah, man!
ＹＯ ユー！ オレのダラーズブラザー呼んであるから
ワックワックしよ～ぜ ナ～ミン！
People like him will all do the same thing in this situation.
この手の輩がやることは万国共通である
Man, this is so cliché it's actually interesting.
かぁ～！ ここまでベタだとすがすがしいね
I know I should help her.
やっぱり 助けるべきだよな
But, how...?
でも どうやって？
Stop it, you guys!
君たち やめたまえ！
No way, I'd get killed.
ダメだ やられる
Then...
じゃあ…
Hey, Sonohara, what a coincidence!
やあ 園原さん 偶然だね
Let's go!
じゃあ
He's so cool!
格好いい
That's it!
これだ これしかない
That's the only way!
She getting bullied?
いじめ？
So, you plan on making them stop?
やめさせに行くつもりなんだ
Also, this city plays host to countless unimaginable events.
そして この街では
想像を超える出来事が度々起きる
Uh, umm...
あっ あの…
Eh? Eh? Eh? What?
なっ 何？
Eh?
Huh?!
J-Just wait a—
ちょっ… ちょっと待って
Da-da-da-da...da.
What?!
何？
Er, umm...
Bullying people isn't cool.
いじめ 格好悪い
Huh?!
Not at all.
実によくない
What's it to you, geezer?
おっさんには関係ねぇだろ
You're right, it doesn't matter to me
whether you get beat up or die in a ditch.
君たちがここで殴られようが のたれ死のうが 関係ない
Even if I do punch you, you're still going to call
me a geezer despite the fact I'm twenty-three,
オレが君たちを殴っても
君たちがまだ２３歳のオレをおっさんと呼ぼうが
so our irrelevancy to each other extends to eternity.
君たちとオレの無関係は永遠だ
Huh?!
Humans are quite spirited.
人間って希薄だよね
Well, my hobby isn't hurting young girls...
まあ オレに女の子を傷つける趣味はないけど
So I decided to make it...stepping on young girls' cell phones.
だから
女の子の携帯を踏みつぶすことを趣味に…するよ
Wai—
Who is this guy?!
何 こいつ
I'm through with this.
飽きちゃった
Stepping on girls' cell phones isn't my hobby anymore.
携帯を踏みつぶす趣味はもうやめよう
Hiroshi!
ヒロシ～！
Yo, yo, yo!
Hey, man!
ヘイ メ～ン！
Violence?
暴力？
Oooh, how scary!
おお～ 怖い 怖い！
Wh-Why you...!
てっ てめぇ！
Whoa, I give up!
おっと～ 降参～！
Wait! Wait!
ああっ 待て！ 待ってくれ～！
I won't forget this!
覚えてろよ～！
The interlopers take to the stage.
妖怪かまいたち 参上
Yeah, you're a good kid, trying to save someone who's getting bullied.
いやぁ～ 本当に偉いよね いじめられてる子を助けようとするなんて
Long time no see, Kida Masaomi.
久しぶりだね 紀田正臣君
Yeah...hi...
ああ… どうも
Those are Raira Academy uniforms, right?
その制服 来良学園だね
Congratulations on getting in.
入学おめでとう
Thank you very much.
ええ お陰さまで
It's rare for you to be here in Ikebukuro, isn't it, Izaya?
珍しいっすね 臨也さんが池袋にいるなんて
This is the Orihara Izaya who we're not supposed to make an enemy of?!
この人が敵に回しちゃいけない 折原臨也？
Oh, he's just my friend.
こいつはオレのただの友達です
I'm Orihara Izaya.
オレは折原臨也 よろしく
Nice to meet you.
りゅ… 竜ヶ峰帝人です
I'm Ryugamine Mikado!
That sounds like the name of an air conditioner.
エアコンみたいな名前だね
Uh, yeah...
So, why are you here in Ikebukuro?
それで なんで池袋に？
I'm here to see someone.
ちょっと人に会いにね
I already met him, though.
もう会えた
No way! That's a convenience store trash can!
うそ… あれ コンビニのゴミ箱？
It just flew over here!
今飛んできた？ なんで？
Why?!
This is bad...
やべぇ～…
I-za-ya...
い～ざ～や～く～ん
A bartender?
バーテンさん？
Didn't I tell you never to come to Ikebukuro again, I-za-ya?!
池袋には二度と来るなって 言わなかったっけか？
い～ざ～や～君よ～！
Shizu-chan...
シズちゃん…
Don't you work over at the west entrance?
君が働いてるのは西口じゃなかったっけ？
I got fired a long time ago.
とっくにクビさ
And I told you to stop calling me that.
それに その呼び方はやめろって言ってんだろ？
I have a name, and it's Heiwajima Shizuo!
オレには平和島静雄って名前があるってよ
Heiwajima Shizuo?
和島静雄？ またまた敵に回しちゃいけない人
Another person we shouldn't make an enemy of!
Oh, Shizu-chan, are you still mad I pinned that crime on you?
やだなぁ シズちゃん
君に罪をなすりつけたこと まだ怒ってるのかな？
No, I'm not.
怒ってないぞ ただ ぶん殴りたいだけさ
I just want to punch the shit out of you.
I'm not good at dealing with you, since you don't listen to reason.
シズちゃんの暴力ってさ
理屈も言葉も通じないんだから 苦手だよ
I'm in trouble now...
困ったなぁ～
Just let me go.
見逃してよ
There he is! That's him!
いた！ あいつだ！
You did a great job of embarrassing me back there!
てめぇ よくも恥かかせてくれたな！
Don't you know what'll happen if you mess with The Dollars?
ダラーズをなめると どうなるか…
Huh?
Is he wearing bartender clothes?
ってか バーテン服？
No way! He wasn't here before!
うそ!? いや さっきはいなかった
He-Heiwajima...Shizuo?!
へ… 平和島静雄!?
Who the hell are you?!
なんだ てめぇら!?
Some people lose the ability to think clearly in the face of fear.
恐怖を前に 人は冷静な判断力を失ってしまう
You were aiming for my head just then, weren't you?
お前 今頭狙ったな？
So you knew that I could die depending on where you hit me, right?
打ち所が悪けりゃ 死んじまうって分かってるよなぁ？
And since you knew that, trying to hit me there means you wanted to kill me, right?
分かってて やったってことは 殺す気だったってことだよなぁ？
Then, you won't complain no matter what I do to you!
じゃあ 何をされても文句はねぇよなぁ？
People who possess overwhelming power tend to inspire instinctual fear.
圧倒的な力を持つ者は
人に本能的な恐怖を抱かせる
To him, acting violent is like wearing clothes—no, he lives solely on violence—no, he's violence incarnate.
暴力が服を着ているような
暴力だけで生きているような
いや 彼そのものが暴力…
That man...
そんな男
You idiots! Don't run away—
バカ 逃げるな！ 相手は…
Alright, see you!
じゃ お疲れ～
I...won't...let...you...run...away!
逃がさねぇ
Wait! How...?
なんで？ どうして上から？
From above...?
He chose the wrong part of my joke to make
fun of, but I'll answer his question anyway.
つっこみ所が間違っているが 念のため答えると
I was making a delivery to a regular customer on the top floor of that building.
ビルの最上階に住むお得意さんのところに出前に来ていたのだ
Simon, you...
サイモン てめぇ…
Shizuo, fighting isn't good.
静雄 ケンカよくないネ～
Shut up!
うるせぇ！ 邪魔すんな！
See how you like it!
Hey, Mikado, now's the time!
おい 帝人 今のうちに…
What? No way! Mikado!
うそ！ 帝人～！
Huh? Wai—Just a—
I can't breathe!
I-I'm sorry!
ご… ごめん
Sometimes, this city can send you a gift.
街が贈り物をくれることもある
A very small, yet large miracle.
とても小さな…だが 大きな奇跡を
Like the possibility that the adventure he'd been looking for—a new story—was about to unfold...
望んでいた冒険
新たな物語が始まる可能性
And...
そして…
Um...
あ あの…
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございました
Eh?
Please excuse me.
失礼します
Eh? Uhh...
And sometimes, nothing unfolds.
何も始まらないこともある
I found you.
見つけた オレの愛
My love...
They said it's The Dollars again.
またダラーズがやったって
I heard! They were fighting with a guy named Heiwajima Shizuo—
知ってる～
平和島静雄って人と真っ昼間から大乱闘でしょ
I heard The Dollars started a fight.
ダラーズがケンカ売ったらしいぜ
They started an impromptu fight with Heiwajima Shizuo?!
静雄とダラーズの抗争勃発
Apparently.
No, that's not it.
I just happened to see the fight, but
those guys are just Dollars impostors.
I'm not talking about that.
Recently, a bunch of people calling themselves
"The Dollars" have been mugging people on the streets.
Eh?
They're scary, they're terrible, those Dollars.
Be careful.
...Thanks.
They sure are scary...
Those Dollars.
Izaya came to Ikebukuro, so just when I figured
I'd snuff him out, Simon jumps in and interferes.
臨也が池袋に来ててさ
今度こそ息の根を止めてやろうと思ったら
サイモンに邪魔された
But, just why did he come here...?
しかし あいつ… 何しに来やがったんだ？
This city is filled with foreigners.
この街は異邦人であふれている
They come here looking for something,
seeking something, wanting to change something.
何かを探し 何かを求め この街にやってくる
何かを変えようと この街に
Welcome, Welcome!
イラッシャ～イ イラッシャ～イ！
It's the same for me.
Sushi's good!
かくいう私も…
Eat sushi!
スシ食いネェ～！
Please listen to my story.
僕の話を聞いてくれ
To the story of me and her; a tale like no other.
他に類のない 僕と彼女の話を
I'd like you to listen to the whole thing.
どうか 最後まで聞いてほしい
Next Time: Living In Isolation.
制作：lastZZZ akira 安静の云 アキラ
You'll surely be kept on the edge of your seat and lose your sanity.
きっと あなたは戦戦慄慄 心神喪失になるだろう
漫游字幕组
http://popgo.net/bbs/